http://www.menopause.org/About-NAMS/privacypolicy

Contact Us
For ProfessionalsMember CenterNAMS CMEMember LoginHow to Join NAMSResearch Mentorship ProgramNCMP CertificationNCMP MaintenanceRelated WebsitesClinician's TextbookMenoPro Mobile App Facts About SERMsVideo Series-2020Video Series-2019Video Series-2018Video Series-2017Video Series-2016Annual Meetings2020 MeetingAward & Scholarship RecipientsCME InformationFAQs Virtual Annual MeetingRegistrationVirtual Meeting AssistanceMeeting AbstractsScientific Program2019 MeetingAward & Scholarship RecipientsCME InformationPremier PartnerScientific ProgramMeeting Abstracts2018 MeetingAward & Scholarship RecipientsCME InformationPremier PartnerScientific ProgramTranslational Science SymposiumMeeting AbstractsFuture MeetingsOther MeetingsPublicationsProfessional PublicationsMenopause Journal ContentsPosition Statements & Other ReportsMenopause Practice TextbookThe Menopause A to Z Slide SetClinical Practice MaterialsBioidentical Hormone TherapyMenopause Health QuestionnaireMenopause QOL Instrument (UQOL)Consumer PublicationsMenopause Guidebook, 9th EditionClinical CornerMenoNotesBioidentical Hormone TherapyNAMS le da la bienvenida a sus lectores hispanosNAMS souhaite la bienvenue aux lectrices francophones Communications from NAMS Medical DirectorOther ResourcesDevelop a Menopause Discussion GroupEvaluating the Scientific LiteratureFor WomenFind a Menopause PractitionerExpert Answers to Frequently Asked Questions About MenopausePerimenopause & Premature Menopause FAQSMenopause FAQs: Understanding the SymptomsHot Flash FAQs: Triggers, Symptoms & TreatmentsMenopause Symptoms FAQsWomen’s Health and Menopause FAQsHormone Therapy & Menopause FAQsMenopause GuidebookMenoNotesMenoPro Mobile AppSexual Health & Menopause OnlineChanges at Midlife How to Navigate This Online ResourceSexual Problems
at MidlifeCauses of Sexual ProblemsEffective Treatments
for Sexual ProblemsReminders and
ResourcesFrequently Asked QuestionsReferences
AcknowledgmentsMenopause Flashes Menopause Symptoms and TreatmentsBone Health and Heart HealthExercise and DietSexual HealthMental Health at MenopauseWomen's Health and MenopauseMenopause GlossaryBook ReviewsRelated WebsitesWomen's Health WebsitesGeneral HealthNutritionWeight ControlFitnessStopping SmokingSubstance AbuseDomestic AbuseHeart HealthOsteoporosisSex IssuesIncontinenceThyroidDiabetesArthritisMental HealthCancerComplementary & Alternative MedicineLiterature SearchesClinical TrialsWhat Selective Estrogen Receptor Modulators (SERMs) Can Do for YouVideo Series-2020Video Series-2019Video Series-2018Video Series-2017Video Series-2016Commercial SupportersAdvertise in Menopause NAMS Corporate Liaison CouncilOutreach OpportunitiesExhibit InformationPress RoomNAMS in the NewsPress ReleasesMedia Award RecipientsMedia PolicyMedia RequestsCommunications from NAMS Medical Director
Privacy Policy
Home
>
About NAMS
>
Privacy Policy
(Last updated 12/22/11) Because NAMS wants to demonstrate commitment to your privacy, the Society discloses its information practices as follows:
What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the website. Which organization is collecting the information. How the information is used. With whom the information may be shared. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under NAMS’s control. How you can correct inaccuracies in the information.
If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact NAMS (info@menopause.org). This section outlines our policies and practices regarding the collection and use of your personal information from your visit to our website (www.menopause.org) and your use of our other Internet services (eg, broadcast email). NAMS has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to maintaining the privacy of visitors to our website and users of our Internet services, and includes our policies for Society members and nonmembers.
Privacy Policy
1. General Website Usage Information
To monitor site usage and improve the quality of our website, we gather general information about the use of our site. We use webserver logs and industry-standard website statistics software to count the number of users who visit our website and to count the number of views of particular pages, as well as to track other general statistics about our website. This information, referred to as “aggregate information,” is kept on the server and compiled by the statistical program. It does not contain any personal information, such as names and email addresses. We do not track individual users’ visits to our website. At times, NAMS may share with third parties the aggregate, anonymous information about overall usage of our website and other Internet services that we collect, in order to provide general information about our Internet services or obtain educational grant funding that supports the development of the site. We do not share any information, including your email address, about specific users. NAMS uses "cookies" in its webstore. Cookies are small data files that are sent by a website and stored on your computer. Cookies are used by most websites (often without the visitor’s knowledge), but NAMS wants its website to provide the highest degree of privacy. Therefore, its webstore uses only temporary session-based cookies for tracking and processing your order, then the cookie disappears when your browser window is closed. You can learn more about cookies by visiting CookieCentral.com. We do not use tracking technologies in our email communications.
2. Information Collected to Process Transactions
When visitors to our website or users of other Internet services apply for or renew membership, order products, register for events, make a donation, participate in a CME activity, or sign up for services, we will collect information necessary to process the transaction. This may include your name, address, telephone and fax numbers, email address, and credit card number or other payment information. This information is encrypted and sent to us using a secure method, in order to assure that your private information, including your email address, is securely and safely transmitted. However, no one can give an absolute assurance that information intended to be maintained as private, whether transmitted via the Internet or otherwise, cannot be accessed inappropriately or unlawfully by third parties. We have taken and will continue to take reasonable steps to ensure the secure and safe transmission of this kind of information. If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, telephone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate user’s personally identifiable information. This can usually be done by emailing info@menopause.org or contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. Please see the section “Members Only” for details of how we may use members’ personal information, including email address, collected during membership application or renewal.
3. Payment Information
Payment information is collected only to process a transaction; this information is kept only to comply with state sales tax laws. While being used to process the transaction, your payment information is stored in an encrypted format and reasonable measures are taken to ensure your payment information is not vulnerable to theft or interception. We will not store your payment information in a manner that is not necessary for processing a transaction. We employ third parties to assist us in fulfilling orders and other requests involving payment, and these third parties will have access to certain personal information, including your email address, in order to perform their services for us. We limit the use of all such personal information by these third parties to performance of such services. When a transaction is submitted on the NAMS website, the user's personal information—including the credit card number—is sent directly to the bank for processing. NAMS does not receive this personal account information. NAMS does not offer or sell products or services for purchase by children.
4. Email Communication
When contacting NAMS at any of the email addresses used for member and nonmember customer assistance (such as info@menopause.org), we may ask for certain information such as your member ID number, name, email address, telephone number, or fax number. When collected for this purpose, the information is used solely to identify and to provide the requested assistance. Messages that you send to NAMS by email may not be secure. We recommend that you do not send any confidential information to us by email. If you choose to forward confidential information by email, you accept the risk that a third party may intercept this information. Please see the next section “Members Only” for details of how we may use members’ email addresses. NAMS will not distribute or sell the email addresses of members or nonmember customers to any third party.
5. Members Only
NAMS offers members certain features and services through the restricted-access “Members Section” of our website. The NAMS membership identification (ID) number is needed to access the Members Section of the site. These 5-digit numbers are provided to NAMS members on their NAMS Membership Card. This ID number should be entered in the box called "User Name." As the password, members should enter their first name, exactly as it appears on the Membership Card. A member's password cannot be changed by the member nor by the NAMS Central Office. NAMS members receive as part of their membership a complimentary subscription of the print and online versions of the journal Menopause. To gain access to the online version at the publisher's website (www.menopausejournal.org), subscribers enter their 12-digit customer number, which appears above the address on the print version's mailing label. The user name and password are established when the online subscription is activated. No cookies are used on this site to allow the Members Section to remember login information. When logging in, if a member chooses the option "save this password in your password list," the password will be saved by Windows Explorer in an encrypted file on the member's hard drive, allowing the member access without further login at the next visit. The password is not saved by the NAMS site. Member profiles are maintained for every active member of the Society in our main membership database. This profile includes information such as member ID number, name, institution/firm, postal address, telephone and fax numbers, and email address. NAMS collects and uses the email addresses of member subscribers to various programs (eg, First-to-Know and Menopause e-Consult e-newsletters) for the purposes of sending the email messages that comprise these services. We may occasionally send email messages with surveys regarding these services. The personal information, including your email address, in the member profiles is occasionally used by NAMS to distribute marketing materials by mail, fax, or email. Members can elect not to receive from NAMS certain printed mailings, faxes, or certain email notices. However, electing not to receive any of these communications may mean that you will not receive important notices about your membership or materials, events, or services that may be useful to you. NAMS occasionally rents the names and postal addresses of its members to third parties for promotional mailings when contents are approved by the NAMS Board of Trustees, but restricts such third parties from otherwise using or retaining such information. Members can elect not to be included in these list rentals. If you are a member and wish not be to included in any of these communications, please contact NAMS using the methods listed in paragraph 11.
6. Annual Meeting Registrations
Currently, the NAMS website does not collect information to process registrations to attend the NAMS Annual Meeting and other large NAMS events. NAMS provides a link from its website to the website of the trusted contracted meeting registration company that processes all online registrations. This company mails all registration reports, including the name of the participant and payment details, to the NAMS Central Office. Registrants’ member status within the Society is confirmed. Member and nonmember registrants are recorded in the NAMS database to allow for certificate processing and verification of continuing education credit hours. Individuals who have attended NAMS meetings in the past are mailed information about future NAMS meetings and events. If you do not want to receive these mailings, contact NAMS as indicated in paragraph 11.
7. Business Transfers
In the event that NAMS goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another organization, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information, including your email address, will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via prominent notice on our website for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users’ personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, they will be given a choice consistent with our notification of changes policy as indicated in paragraph 10.
8. Links to Other Websites
The NAMS website and many NAMS print publications contain many links to other websites. NAMS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites. Please check with the other sites to determine their privacy policies.
9. Disclosure of Personal Information
NAMS will disclose your personal information, including your email address, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on NAMS or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights of property of NAMS; and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of the NAMS membership and staff, its website, or the public.
10. Notification of Changes
This privacy statement will occasionally be updated to reflect new features and services or new privacy practices. The latest version will always be posted on our website.
11. Contacting NAMS About Privacy Issues
We welcome your comments, suggestions, and questions about our privacy statement and our privacy practices. If you elect not to receive certain forms of communication from NAMS and third parties, please contact us.
Email:  info@menopause.org Phone:  440/442-7550 Fax:  440/442-2660 Postal mail: The North American Menopause Society
5900 Landerbrook Drive, Suite 390
Mayfield Heights, Ohio 44124, USA
About NAMSAnnual ReportsBoard of TrusteesContact UsDonateEndowmentsExecutive Directors EmeritiFundraising Compliance InformationHonorary MembersHow NAMS Is FundedMission, Vision and BylawsPast PresidentsPrivacy Policy
NAMS is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit scientific organization. This website is totally funded by
The North American Menopause Society. No commercial advertisements are accepted.
Please note that the information contained on this website cannot replace a health professional-patient relationship. Consumers should always consult with a professional for diagnosis and treatment for specific health problems.
Copyright© 2020 |  Home
|  Privacy Policy  |   Site Map |
30050 Chagrin Blvd, Suite 120W - Pepper Pike, OH 44124, USA
Telephone: 440/442-7550 - Fax: 440/442-2660  - Email: info@menopause.org
Please enter a valid email address.
Your Name:
Your Friend's E-mail:
Optional Message:
255 character limit
Your friend will receive an e-mail invitation to view this page, but we will not store or share this e-mail address with outside parties.
To submit the email please enter the sum of 6 + 7.
